<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE isview [
    <!ENTITY mdash "&#x2014;">
]>
<InlineHelp>

<StartPage>
  <!--<Task icon="FILE" cmd="new">Create a <Bold>New</Bold> Package</Task>-->
  <Task icon="FOLDER" cmd="open">Open an <Bold>Existing</Bold> Package</Task>
  <Help topic="VPE_Saving">Saving a Virtual Package</Help>
  <Help topic="VPE_ConfigureMultSettings">Configuring the Value of a Setting for More Than One Item at a Time</Help>
  <Help topic="VPE_ConflictResolve">Testing and Troubleshooting Virtual Packages</Help>
  <Resource icon="HELPLIB" topic="VPE_Using">Help Library</Resource>
  <Resource icon="SEARCH" href="http://community.installshield.com/">AdminStudio Community</Resource>
</StartPage>

<!--Root nodes-->

<Topic id="Category:Package Information">
<p>Describe and configure your virtual package.</p>
<dl>
<dt>General Information</dt><dd>Specify or view basic information such as the name of the virtual package and details such as the package GUID and version number. This view also shows history information such as each date on which the package was saved. <help topic="VPE_RefGenInfoView.htm" text="plain">Read more about General Information</help>.</dd>
<when is="appv-5">
<dt>Asset Intelligence</dt><dd>View and edit information identifying this application. Typically these values are read in from the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key. <help topic="VPE_RefAssetIntelligenceView.htm" text="plain">Read more about Asset Intelligence</help>.</dd>
</when>
<when is="appv-4">
<dt>Dependencies</dt><dd>Specify other App-V packages that the open App-V package requires. <help topic="VPE_RefDpndcsView.htm" text="plain">Read more about Dependencies</help>.</dd>
</when>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="Category:Application Data">
<when is="appv-4">
<p>Specify the files, folders, and registry entries that make up your virtual application. Define targets and the entry points that launch the targets in the virtual environment.</p>
</when>
<when not="appv-4">
<p>Specify the files, folders, registry entries, and file extensions that make up your virtual application. Define targets and the entry points that launch the targets in the virtual environment.</p>
</when>
<dl>
<dt>Files and Folders</dt><dd>Specify the files and folders that are in the App-V package. Extract folders and files from the App-V package file (.appv or .sft) to a location that you specify. <help topic="VPE_RefFilesFoldrsView.htm" text="plain">Read more about Files and Folders</help></dd>
<dt>Registry</dt><dd>The Registry view enables you to define registry keys, values, and data for your App-V package. <help topic="VPE_RefRegistryView.htm" text="plain">Read more about Registry</help></dd>
<dt>Shortcuts</dt><dd>Define the targets for your virtual application, and define entry points such as shortcuts for each target. These entry points enable end users to launch an App-V application from within the virtual environment. <help topic="VPE_RefShortcutsView.htm" text="plain">Read more about Shortcuts</help></dd>
<when not="appv-4">
<dt>File Extensions</dt><dd>Associate file extensions with a target in your virtual package, and set up one or more verbs for the file extension. <help topic="VPE_Ref_Exten.htm" text="plain">Read more about File Extensions</help></dd>
</when>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="Category:System Configuration">
<p>Configure your virtual package so that the application can be run in the virtual environment.</p>
<dl>
<dt>Virtual Services</dt><dd>Configure services that you want to include in your App-V package so that they are available in the virtual environment. <help topic="VPE_RefVirtServicesView.htm" text="plain">Read more about Virtual Services</help></dd>
<when not="appv-4">
<dt>Environment Variables</dt><dd>Create environment variables&mdash;name and value pairs&mdash;that the virtual package requires. <help topic="VPE_RefEnvironmentView.htm" text="plain">Read more about Environment Variables</help></dd>
<dt>Application Paths</dt><dd>Define data that the App-V package should use as a private search path for the specified application's DLL files. <help topic="VPE_RefApplicationPathsView.htm" text="plain">Read more about Application Paths</help></dd>
</when>
</dl>
</Topic>


<!-- General Information -->

<Topic id="VpePackage:Cat:App-V">
<p>Use the App-V area of the General Information view settings to view or specify basic information such as the name of the virtual package and details such as the package GUID and version number.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVName">
<p>Enter a name for the App-V package.</p>
<tip>
<p>If your virtual package contains multiple applications, you can specify the name that identifies the entire package. For example, Microsoft Office could be used to identify a package that contains Microsoft Word and Microsoft Excel applications that run in the same virtual environment.</p>
</tip>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVComments">
<p>Enter a short description of the App-V package.</p>
<p>This setting is optional.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVPublisher">
<p>This setting shows publisher of the applications contained in this App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVVersion">
<p>This setting shows the main software version of the applications in this App-V package.</p>
</Topic>
  
<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVOS">
<p>The OS setting and its subsettings let you specify one or more operating systems on which the application can be run.</p>
<p>If the application is operating system independent, select False for all of the OS subsettings.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVPackageGuid">
<p>This read-only setting shows the globally unique identifier (GUID) that is associated with the App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVVersionGuid"><!--App-V 5-->
<p>This read-only setting shows the globally unique identifier (GUID) that is associated with the version (revision) of the App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVPackageVersion">
<p>This read-only setting shows the version number of the App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVClientVersion">
<p>This read-only setting shows the minimum version number of the Application Virtualization Client that is required to use the App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVRootFolder">
<p>This setting specifies the root folder of the App-V package's file system. During run time, the Application Virtualization Client mounts the package's file system to the App-V virtual drive; the Q drive is the default. The long and short names of the root folder must be unique because two packages with the same root folder name cannot be deployed simultaneously.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVFB1Size">
<p>This read-only setting indicates the size of the primary feature block, the part of the App-V package that is required to start the application.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVFileSize">
<p>This read-only setting indicates the size of the entire package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVCompression">
<p>Specify whether you want the App-V package's contents to be compressed.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVSecdEnforced">
<p>This read-only setting indicates whether security descriptors of the application in the App-V package are enforced after it is deployed to the client system.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVLocalInteractionAllowed">
<p>Specify whether you want named objects (events, mutexes, semaphores, file mappings, and mailslots) and COM objects to be created in the global namespace. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Yes</dt><dd>Named objects and COM objects are created in the global namespace, allowing virtual applications to interact with the applications of the client operating system.</dd>
<dt>No</dt><dd>Named objects and COM objects are isolated inside the virtual environment.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:Cat:App-V Server URL">
<p>Use the App-V Server URL area of the General Information view settings to specify the location from which the App-V package is streamed.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVServerProtocol">
<p>Select the protocol that you want to use to stream the sequenced application package from the virtual application server to an Application Virtualization Client. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>RTSP</dt><dd>The real-time streaming protocol streams the App-V package. This is the default option.</dd>
<dt>RTSPS</dt><dd>The real-time streaming protocol with transport layer security streams the App-V package.</dd>
<dt>FILE</dt><dd>The App-V package are streamed from a file share.</dd>
<dt>HTTP</dt><dd>The hypertext transport protocol streams the App-V package.</dd>
<dt>HTTPS</dt><dd>The secure hypertext transport protocol streams the App-V package.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVServerHost">
<p>Specify the host&mdash;the virtual application server or the load balancer in front of a group of virtual application servers that stream the App-V package to the Application Virtualization Client. You can either specify a static host name or IP address, or you can enter <input>%SFT_SOFTGRIDSERVER%</input> to indicate an environment variable.</p>
<note>
<p>If you enter <input>%SFT_SOFTGRIDSERVER%</input>, you must set up the SFT_SOFTGRIDSERVER system environment variable on each Application Virtualization Client. The value of this environment variable should be the name or IP address of the host.</p>
<p>When you assign the variable on a client system, any Application Virtualization Client session that is running on the system must be closed and reopened; otherwise, the session is not aware of the new application source.</p>
</note>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVServerPort">
<p>Specify the port on which the virtual application server or the load balancer listens for Application Virtualization Client requests for the package. The default port is 554.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVServerPath">
<p>Specify the relative path on the virtual application server where the App-V package is stored. This is also the path from which the App-V package is streamed.</p>
<p>If the App-V package is stored in a subdirectory of CONTENT, the path must be specified in this setting; otherwise, you can leave this setting blank.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVNamedObjectsInteraction">
<p>Enable this option to allow all named objects to interact with the local system. The default setting is 'False' to keep these objects isolated from the local system.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVComObjectInteraction">
<p>Enable this option to allow COM to interact with the local system. The default setting is 'Isolated' to keep the COM components isolated from the local system.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVComInProcessEnabled">
<p>Enable this option to allow in-process COM to interact with the local system. COM Object Interaction option has to be set to 'Integrated' to for this option to have effect.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVComOutOfProcessEnabled">
<p>Enable this option to allow out-of-process COM to interact with the local system. COM Object Interaction option has to be set to 'Integrated' for this option to have effect.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVFullVFSWriteMode">
<p>This is a new setting in App-V 5 SP2 Hotfix 4 that enables a virtual application to write to its VFS files and folders. Select 'True' to enable this setting. The default behavior is to leave it at 'False'.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpePackage:AppVEnableBrowserHelperObjects">
<p>This is a new setting in App-V 5.1 that allows enabling or disabling browser helper object extensions. Select 'True' to enable this setting. The default behavior is to leave it at 'True'.
</p>
<p>This setting will appear disabled for packages that do not contain any browser helper object extensions.
</p>
</Topic>


<!-- Asset Intelligence -->
<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:Cat:General">
<p>Use the Asset Intelligence area to view and edit information identifying this application. Typically these values are read in from the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:SoftwareCode">
<p>This corresponds to the name of the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key. For MSI installations that were converted to App-V, this is the ProductCode.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:ProductName">
<p>This corresponds to DisplayName value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:ProductVersion">
<p>This corresponds to DisplayVersion value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:Publisher">
<p>This corresponds to Publisher value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:ProductID">
<p>This corresponds to ProductID value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key. Often times this can correspond to a serial number or product SKU.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:Language">
<p>This corresponds to Language value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key. This should be a numeric language identifier.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:ChannelCode">
<p>This may correspond to ChannelCode value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:InstallDate">
<p>This corresponds to InstallDate value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key. It is the last time this product received service.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:RegisteredUser">
<p>This may correspond to RegisteredUser value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:InstalledLocation">
<p>This corresponds to InstalledLocation value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:CM_DSLID">
<p>This corresponds to Definite Software Library ID (DSLID) if one exists.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:VersionMajor">
<p>This corresponds to VersionMajor value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key. It is a numerical representation of a part of the product version.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:VersionMinor">
<p>This corresponds to VersionMinor value under the Add/Remove Programs Uninstall registry key. It is a numerical representation of a part of the product version.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:ServicePack">
<p>This may correspond to the service pack level of the product.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:UpgradeCode">
<p>This may correspond to the UpgradeCode of the MSI used to originally install this application.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAssetIntel:OSComponent">
<p>A value of 0 indicates that the application is not part of the OS, and a value of 1 indicates that it is part of the OS.</p>
</Topic>

<!-- Dependencies -->

<Topic id="VpeDep:Cat:General">
<p>Use the General area for the selected .sft file in the Dependencies view settings to identify a required App-V package that the open App-V package requires.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeDep:Name">
<p>This read-only setting shows the name of the required .sft file.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeDep:Guid">
<p>This read-only setting shows the globally unique identifier (GUID) that is associated with the required App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeDep:SysGuardFile">
<p>This read-only setting shows the folder and name of the required App-V package's SysGuard file (<filename>osguard.cp</filename>). The SysGuard file describes how the virtual environment needs to be set up.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeDep:Href">
<p>Enter the URL for the published location of the required App-V package on the virtual application server. Typically, this location matches the App-V server URL for the App-V package that contains the dependency.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeDependent:Cat:General">
<p>Use the General area for the selected target in the Dependencies view settings to specify whether a required App-V package is mandatory in order for the App-V package that you are editing in the Virtual Package Editor to run properly.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeDependent:Name">
<p>This read-only setting shows the name of the target that is associated with the required App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeDependent:Mandatory">
<p>Specify whether the required App-V package is mandatory in order for the primary package (the App-V package that you are editing in the Virtual Package Editor) to run properly.</p>
<p>Note that if the dependency is mandatory, the primary package cannot run without loading the required package.</p>
</Topic>



<!-- Files and Folders -->

<Topic id="VpeFolder:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area of the Files and Folders view to configure and view information about the selected folder.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area of the Files and Folders view to configure and view information about the selected file.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:Name">
<p>Enter the name of the file or folder in the App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:ShortName">
<p>Enter the name of the file or folder using the 8.3 format.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:Path">
<p>This read-only setting shows the location of the file or folder in the App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:Size">
<p>This read-only setting shows the size of the file.</p>
<p>This setting applies to files; it does not apply to folders.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:Attributes">
<p>To set various attributes for the selected file or folder, use the following settings:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Read-Only</dt><dd>Specify whether the file is read-only&mdash;protected from being changed or accidentally deleted.</dd>
<dt>Hidden</dt><dd>Specify whether the file or folder is visible in directory listings when default folder viewing options are enabled.</dd>
<dt>System</dt><dd>Specify whether the file or folder is a system file or folder that the operating system uses.</dd>
<dt>Archive</dt><dd>Specify whether the file or folder should be archived. Some applications use this attribute to determine whether to back up a file or folder.</dd>
<dt>Normal</dt><dd>Specify whether the file should have its other attributes configured. Selecting True for this setting is valid only if False is selected for the other True-False attributes.</dd>
<dt>Not Content-Indexed</dt><dd>Specify whether you want to avoid indexing the contents of the file or folder for faster searching.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:Created">
<p>This read-only setting shows the date and time when the file or folder was created.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:Modified">
<p>This read-only setting shows the date and time when the file or folder was last modified.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:SourcePath">
<p>If the file has not yet been saved as part of the App-V package, this read-only setting shows the fully qualified path of the source file.</p>
<p>This setting applies to files; it does not apply to folders.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:Font">
<p>Specify whether you want the font to be registered in the virtual environment.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:AppVFeatureBlock1">
<p>Specify whether the file is part of the primary feature block, the part of the App-V package that is required to start the application.</p>
<p>This setting applies to files; it does not apply to folders.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:AppVGuid">
<p>This read-only setting shows the globally unique identifier (GUID) that is associated with the file or folder.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:AppVVersion">
<p>For a file, this read-only setting shows the version number of the App-V package that corresponds with the last time that the file was modified.</p>
<p>For any folder other than the root folder, this read-only setting shows the latest version number of the App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:AppVVfsPath">
<p>This read-only field contains the path that is used by App-V client to overlay the virtual file or folder onto the corresponding physical location. It is always set for files that are inside of the VFS folder. And it is set for folders found inside the VFS folder only when the folder's isolation setting has been set as 'Override' - this indicates that the folder should be fully virtualized.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:AppVDataType">
<p>Specify the data type of the file or folder. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Application Data</dt><dd>Changes to the file or folder are saved for all users of the App-V package on the client system.</dd>
<dt>User Data</dt><dd>Changes to the file or folder are saved for only the logged-on user.</dd>
<dt>Unspecified</dt><dd>The data type of the file or folder is not configured.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:AppVOverride">
<p>Specify whether you want the Application Virtualization Client to overwrite the file or folder when the App-V package is upgraded and streamed from the App-V server to the client.</p>
<p>If you select No, the Application Virtualization Client determines whether to overwrite the file or folder during an upgrade. In general, if User Data is selected for the App-V Data Type setting, the file or folder is not overwritten during an upgrade; otherwise, the file or folder is overwritten.</p>
<note><p>According to Microsoft documentation, the override functionality is deprecated as of Application Virtualization Client 4.5.</p></note>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFile:AppVIsolation">
<p>Specify whether you want the selected folder in the App-V package to override the corresponding folder on the client system. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Override</dt>
<dd>The App-V application sees only the file content of the folder that is inside the App-V package. For an App-V 5.x package this setting is inherited by all sub-folders. Override isolation setting is also referred to as 'Fully Virtualized.'</dd>
<dt>Merge</dt>
<dd>The App-V application sees a merged view of the file content inside the App-V package and of the file content of the corresponding folder on the physical client system.</dd>
</dl>
<p>This setting applies to only to folders and not to files.</p>
<note>
  <p>For App-V 4.x packages, setting this option to 'Override' automatically sets the VFS path, and setting this option to 'Merge' automatically clears the VFS path.</p>
</note>
</Topic>
<!-- Registry -->

<Topic id="VpeRegKey:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area of the Registry view to configure and view information about the selected registry key.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeReg:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area of the Registry view to configure and view information about the selected registry value.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeReg:Name">
<p>Enter the name of the selected registry key or value.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeReg:ValueData">
<p>Enter the data for the selected registry value, or (for a registry key) enter the data for the selected key's default value.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeReg:ValueType">
<p>Select the appropriate type of registry data for the selected registry entry.</p>
<p>If you select the REG_QWORD type, ensure that the operating system of the client system supports it.</p>
<p>This setting applies to registry values; it does not apply to registry keys. The default value of a registry key is always the REG_SZ type of value.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeReg:AppVOverride">
<p>Specify whether you want the selected registry key in the App-V package to override the corresponding key on the client system. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Override</dt><dd>The App-V application sees the registry content that is inside the App-V package for this key and all subkeys. Thus, the application does not see any registry content from the physical client system.</dd>
<dt>Merge</dt><dd>The App-V application sees a merged view of the registry content inside the App-V package and of the registry content on the physical client system. If the registry key has subkeys on the physical client system but not in the App-V package, these keys are merged into the registry view that is available to the App-V application. However, registry values that are on the physical client system and that are in registry keys that also exist in the App-V package are not merged into the App-V application's registry view.</dd>
</dl>
<tip><p>If your virtual package includes a registry key that has multiple subkeys whose Isolation setting should be configured with the same value, you can quickly change the value of the Isolation setting for all of that key's subkeys simultaneously. You can also quickly configure the Isolation setting for all of the subkeys that belong to multiple parent keys. To learn how, see <help topic="VPE_OverrideChildReg.htm">Configuring the App-V Override Setting for All of the Subkeys Under One or More Keys</help>.</p></tip>
<p>This setting applies to registry keys; it does not apply to registry values.</p>
</Topic>


<!-- Shortcuts -->

<Topic id="VpeTarget:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area for a target that is selected in the Shortcuts view to define a target in your App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeTarget:Name">
<p>Enter the name of the target.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeTarget:Target">
<p>Enter the path and file name of the file in the App-V package or on the client system that should be launched when end users launch the target's shortcut or other entry point. As an alternative to manually entering a value, you can click the Browse This Package button or the Browse Your Computer button to browse to the target file.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeTarget:Icon">
<p>Enter the path to the icon file (.ico, .exe, or .dll) that contains the icon resource for the shortcut. The location can be in the App-V package, or on your computer or the network. As an alternative to manually entering a value, you can click the Browse This Package button or the Browse Your Computer button to browse to the icon.</p>
<p>If the icon file that you specify contains more than one icon resource, after the icon path, add a comma and then the index number. For example, 0 refers to the first icon in the file, 1 refers to the second icon, and 2 refers to the third icon. To specify the third icon in <example>C:\MyIcons.dll</example>, enter the following:</p>
<p><input>C:\MyIcons.dll,2</input></p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeTarget:TargetVersion">
<p>Enter the version number of the target.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeTarget:Arguments">
<p>Enter the command-line arguments for the shortcut. These arguments work in the same way as any other command-line arguments. For example, you can link a file to an executable file or cause an executable file to run silently by passing command-line arguments.</p>
<note><p>Verify that the syntax is correct because the Virtual Package Editor does not do this.</p></note>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeTarget:WorkingDirectory">
<p>Enter the working directory for the target. As an alternative to manually entering a value, you can click the Browse This Package button or the Browse Your Computer button to select or create the directory.</p>
<p>The working directory is the default directory that is displayed in standard file-opening and file-saving dialog boxes, as well as the current directory used by the App-V application.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeTarget:TerminateChildren">
<p>Specify whether you want all of the applications and processes that were launched by the App-V application to be closed when the end user exits the App-V application.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeShortcut:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area for a shortcut that is selected in the Shortcuts view to configure a shortcut in your App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeShortcut:Name">
<p>Enter the name of the shortcut as it should appear on the client system.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeShortcut:Location">
<p>Enter the path to the folder that contains the shortcut file. As an alternative to manually entering a value, you can click the Browse Your Computer button or select a predefined folder from the drop-down list.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeEnv:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area for an environment variable that is selected in the view to configure an environment variable in your App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeEnv:Name">
<p>Enter the name of the environment variable that you want to configure for the virtual application.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeEnv:Value">
<p>Enter the path or value for this environment variable.</p>
<p>To enter multiple paths, separate the paths with a semicolon (;).</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area for a file extension that is selected in the view to set up a file association for your App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:Cat:File Extension Settings">
  <p>The File Extension Settings area can be used to specify the settings for the extension that is part of this file type association.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:Cat:ProgId Settings">
  <p>The ProgId Settings area can be used to specify the settings for the ProgId that is part of this file type association.</p>
</Topic>
  
<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:Cat:Shell New Settings">
  <p>The Shell New Settings area can be used to enable and customize the 'New' right-click context menu for this file extension.</p>
</Topic>
  
<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:Extension">
<when not="appv-4">
<p>To associate a file extension with the App-V application, enter the extension, including the dot&mdash;for example, enter <input>txt</input> instead of <input>.txt</input>.</p>
</when>
<when is="appv-4">
<p>To associate a file extension with the App-V application, enter the extension. It is not necessary to enter the dot&mdash;for example, enter <input>txt</input> instead of <input>.txt</input>.</p>
</when>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:Description">
<p>Enter the description text that you want to display for this file extension in the Application Virtualization Client.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:MIME">
<p>Enter the MIME type that is associated with the file extension.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:ProgId">
<p>Enter the program identifier&mdash;ProgId, also known as <em>application identifier</em> or <em>tag name</em>&mdash;that you want to associate with the file extension. A file type's ProgId is an arbitrary string, but it should be unique on the client system. One ProgId naming convention is to append the word <em>file</em> to your extension without a dot&mdash;the .ext extension might use the ProgId <em>extfile</em>. Another convention is to name a file&mdash;type ProgId after the application that is used to open the file type, as in <input>SampleApp.Document</input>.</p>
<p>For example, an <example>.xyz</example> file extension could point to an <example>xyzfile</example> ProgId, and all of the <example>.xyz</example> file-type information would be registered under <example>xyzfile</example>.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:Icon">
<p>Enter the path to the icon file (.ico, .exe, or .dll) that contains the icon resource for the file extension. The location can be in the App-V package, or on your computer or the network. As an alternative to manually entering a value, you can click the Browse This Package button or the Browse Your Computer button to browse to the icon.</p>
<p>If the icon file that you specify contains more than one icon resource, after the icon path, add a comma and then the index number. For example, 0 refers to the first icon in the file, 1 refers to the second icon, and 2 refers to the third icon. To specify the third icon in the icon file, enter the following after the icon file path:</p>
<p><input>, 2</input></p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:InfoTip">
<p>Enter the text that you want to be displayed when an end user moves the mouse pointer over a file with this type of file extension.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:PerceivedType">
<p>Select the appropriate type of file.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:FileTypeAttributes">
<p>To set various file type attributes for the file association, select the appropriate option for each of the following settings:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Open Is Safe</dt><dd>Specify whether the open verb can be used safely for downloaded files that have this file extension.</dd>
<dt>Always Unsafe</dt><dd>Specify whether files that have this file extension should be considered to be a possible security risk.</dd>
<dt>Always Show Extension</dt><dd>Specify whether you want the file extension to be displayed with the file name, even if the client system is configured to hide extensions for known file types.</dd>
<dt>No Recent Documents</dt><dd>Specify whether you want to exclude files with this extension from the Recent Documents folder.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeFileAssoc:ShellNewEnabled">
<p>Specify whether you want to include this file type in the submenu that is displayed when end users click New on the context menu in Windows Explorer.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area for a verb that is selected in the view to specify details such as the name and description of the verb.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:Target">
<p>Specify the path to the .exe file for which you are creating a verb for the file extension association.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:Name">
<p>Enter the name of the verb, such as <example>Open</example> or <example>Print</example>, that you want to be used when an end user right-clicks a file with the selected extension and then clicks the corresponding command.</p>
<p>To include an underlined letter that indicates that end users can click the letter to select the command, precede that letter with an ampersand (&amp;). For example, to display <uielement>Open</uielement> (with an underlined letter <em>O</em>) on the context menu for this file extension, enter the following:</p>
<p><input>&amp;Open</input></p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:DisplayName">
<p>Enter the text that you want to display for this verb on the context menu that Windows Explorer displays when an end user right-clicks a file with the associated file extension.</p>
<p>To include an underlined letter that indicates that end users can click the letter to select the command, precede that letter with an ampersand (&amp;). For example, to display <uielement>Open with SampleApp</uielement> (with an underlined letter <em>O</em>) on the context menu for this file extension, enter <input>&amp;Open with SampleApp</input>.</p>
<p>This setting is optional. If you do not specify a display name, the name of the verb as it appears in the Name setting is used on the context menu for a file with this file extension on the client system. Note that if you use one of the canonical verbs&mdash;such as open, print, or find&mdash;and you do not specify a display name, Windows automatically localizes the verb on each system.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:Arguments">
<p>Enter the command-line arguments for the verb.</p>
<note><p>Verify that the syntax is correct because the Virtual Package Editor does not do this.</p></note>
<tip><p>Use %1 in the argument for the selected file name. For example, if <commandline>-p %1</commandline> is the argument for the verb, and the end user right-clicks the file <directory>C:\File.ext</directory> and then clicks the command for this verb, the command-line argument becomes <commandline>-p C:\File.ext</commandline>. In some cases, it is necessary to enclose the %1 argument in quotation marks&mdash;as in <input>"%1"</input>&mdash;to correctly handle file names that contain spaces.</p></tip>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:Cat:Dynamic Data Exchange">
<p>If your App-V application supports dynamic data exchange (DDE), use the settings in the Dynamic Data Exchange area for a verb that is selected in the view to configure DDE settings for the verb.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:DdeCommand">
<p>Enter the DDE command for the verb.</p>
<note><p>Verify that the syntax is correct because the Virtual Package Editor does not do this.</p></note>
<tip><p>Use %1 in the argument in place of the file name. In some cases, it is necessary to enclose the %1 argument in quotation marks&mdash;as in <input>"%1"</input>&mdash;to correctly handle file names that contain spaces.</p></tip>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:DdeIfexec">
<p>Enter the DDE command that you want to use if the DDE conversation cannot be initiated.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:DdeApplication">
<p>Enter the application name that you want use to establish the DDE conversation. If you leave this setting blank, the DDE Command setting is used as the application name.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeVerb:DdeTopic">
<p>Enter the name that you want to use as the topic name of the DDE conversation. If you leave this setting blank, <em>System</em> is used as the topic name.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeScript:Cat:General">
<p>Use the General area for a script that is selected in the Shortcuts view to configure information such as the type and timing of the script.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeScript:Event">
<p>Select the timing for the script that you want to launch. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Pre-stream</dt><dd>The script or executable file runs after the end user launches the App-V application, but before feature block 1 of the application is streamed to the client system and before the virtual environment is set up. This type of script or executable file is run outside the virtual environment.</dd>
<dt>Post-stream</dt><dd>The script or executable file runs after the end user launches the App-V application and after feature block 1 of the application is streamed to the client system, but before the virtual environment is set up. This type of script or executable file is run either inside or outside the virtual environment.</dd>
<dt>Pre-launch</dt><dd>The script or executable file runs after the end user launches the App-V application, after feature block 1 of the application is streamed to the client system, and after the virtual environment is set up. This type of script or executable file is run either inside or outside the virtual environment.</dd>
<dt>Post-launch</dt><dd>The script or executable file runs after the App-V application is launched, but before the end user has access to the application. This type of script or executable file is run either inside or outside the virtual environment.</dd>
<dt>Post-shutdown</dt><dd>The script or executable file runs after the App-V application has been closed. This type of script is run outside the virtual environment.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeScript:Type">
<p>Specify the type of script that you want to be run. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Single command (HREF)</dt><dd>The App-V package references an external script or an executable file. The contents of the script are launched directly on the client system. The Command Prompt window is not displayed unless the process that is being called opens it.</dd>
<dt>Command script (SCRIPTBODY)</dt><dd>The contents of the script are stored in the App-V package and copied to a temporary .bat file in the root folder (typically under the Q drive) of the App-V package on the client system. The .bat file is launched from a visible Command Prompt window.</dd>
</dl>
<p>You can use either type of scripting to call an executable file that exists in the folder on the virtual application server where the App-V package is stored.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeScript:Protect">
<p>Specify whether to run the script or executable file inside the virtual environment. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Yes</dt><dd>The script or executable file is run inside the virtual environment. Protected scripts are useful for troubleshooting issues in the virtual environment.</dd>
<dt>No</dt><dd>The script or executable file is run outside the virtual environment. Unprotected scripts are useful for modifying the client system.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeScript:Wait">
<p>Specify whether to wait for the script or executable file to complete before continuing to the next scheduled task&mdash;either another script or the appropriate subsequent event.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeScript:Timeout">
<p>Enter the maximum number of seconds to wait for the script or executable file to complete before continuing. To wait until the script or executable file completes, enter the number 0 or leave this setting blank.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeScript:SuccessResult">
<p>Enter the return code that indicates that the script or executable file finished successfully. This setting is optional.</p>
<p>For information on triggering the appropriate behavior if the script fails or succeeds, see <help topic="VPE_ScriptFailure.htm">Causing the App-V Application to Close After a Script Failure</help>.</p>
<note><p>If you specify Post-shutdown for the Event setting, any value that you specify for the Success Result setting is ignored.</p></note>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeScript:AbortResult">
<p>Enter the return code that indicates that the script or executable file failed. This setting is optional.</p>
<p>For information on triggering the appropriate behavior if the script fails or succeeds, see <help topic="VPE_ScriptFailure.htm">Causing the App-V Application to Close After a Script Failure</help>.</p>
<note><p>If you specify Post-shutdown for the Event setting, any value that you specify for the Abort Result setting is ignored.</p></note>
</Topic>


<!-- Services -->

<Topic id="VpeService:Cat:General">
<p>Use the General area of the Virtual Services view settings to specify information such as the name and location of the virtual service, as well as the type of service. This area is also where you specify when the service should be started.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Name">
<p>Enter the name of the service. The name that you enter is used on the service's Properties dialog box. (To access an installed service's properties: In the Services administrative tool, right-click the service and then click Properties.)</p>
<p>The maximum number of characters that is allowed is 256. The forward slash (/) and the backslash (\) are not valid characters for service names.</p>
<p>The case of the name that you enter is preserved in the service control manager. Display name comparisons are always case-insensitive.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:DisplayName">
<p>Enter the name that you want to be displayed for this service in the service control manager and in other user interfaces. The maximum number of characters that is allowed is 256.</p>
<p>The case of the display name that you enter is preserved in the service control manager. Display name comparisons are always case-insensitive.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:ImagePath">
<p>Enter the fully qualified path to the executable file for the service. If the path contains one or more spaces, surround the path with quotation marks. You can include arguments that you want to be passed for a service that starts automatically.</p>
<p>As an alternative to manually entering the path, you can click the Browse This Package button to browse to the executable file.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Type">
<p>Select the type of service that you are installing.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Interactive">
<p>Specify whether you want the service to be able to interact with users.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Start">
<p>Specify when to start the service. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Automatic</dt><dd>The service starts automatically when the system starts.</dd>
<dt>On Demand</dt><dd>The service starts when the service is requested through the service control manager.</dd>
<dt>Never (Disabled)</dt><dd>The service cannot be started.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:ErrorControl">
<p>Select the appropriate severity of the error to indicate the action that the service control manager should perform if the service fails to start. Available options are:</p>
<dl>
<dt>Ignore</dt><dd>Ignore the error and continue with the service startup.</dd>
<dt>Normal</dt><dd>Log the error and continue with the service startup.</dd>
<dt>Severe</dt><dd>Log the error. If the last-known good configuration is being started, continue with the service startup. Otherwise, restart the system with the last-known good configuration.</dd>
<dt>Critical</dt><dd>Log the error. If the last-known good configuration is being started, the service startup fails. Otherwise, restart the system with the last-known good configuration.</dd>
</dl>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Group">
<p>Enter the name of the load-ordering group, if any, of which this service is a member.</p>
<p>Note that this setting can override the value of the Service Dependencies setting.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:GroupDependencies">
<p>To specify one or more load-ordering groups that this service requires, click the ellipsis button (...) in this setting. When you do so, the Edit Value dialog box opens, enabling you to specify one or more groups. Enter each group on a separate line.</p>
<p>The system attempts to start at least one member of the load-ordering group before starting this service.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:ServiceDependencies">
<p>To specify one or more services that this service requires, click the ellipsis button (...) in this setting. When you do so, the Edit Value dialog box opens, enabling you to specify one or more services. Enter each service on a separate line.</p>
<p>The system attempts to start at least one member of the load-ordering group before starting this service.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Cat:Error Handling">
<p>Use the Error Handling area of the Virtual Services view settings to specify what behavior should occur if the service fails.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:ResetPeriod">
<p>Specify the amount of time (in seconds) between the reset intervals for the service's failure count. As an alternative, you can select one of the values from the list in this setting.</p>
<p>The service control manager counts the number of times that the service has failed since the system was last restarted. When this interval has elapsed, the count is reset to the number 0 if the service has not failed during the reset period. When the service fails, the system performs an action that is specified for the First Error setting, the Second Error setting, or the Additional Errors setting, depending on how many errors have occurred since the last failure count reset or system restart.</p>
<p>To indicate that the failure count should never be reset, select Never or enter a value of -1.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:RebootMessage">
<p>Specify the message that should be displayed before the computer is restarted in response to an error.</p>
<p>Note that Reboot the Computer must be listed as one of the action types for the First Error setting, the Second Error setting, or the Additional Errors setting; otherwise, the Reboot Message setting is ignored.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Command">
<p>Specify the command line that should be run if the Run a Command option is selected for the First Error, Second Error, or Additional Errors setting, and the first, second, or subsequent error occurs during service startup. Programs or scripts that you specify should not require input from end users.</p>
<p>The command line that you specify is used to create a new process that runs under the same account as the service.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Action1">
<p>Select the action that you want the service control manager to perform the first time that the service fails.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Action1Delay">
<p>Specify the time (in milliseconds) that the service control manager should wait before performing the action that is specified in the First Error setting. As an alternative, you can select one of the values from the list in this setting.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Action2">
<p>Select the action that you want the service control manager to perform the second time that the service fails.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Action2Delay">
<p>Specify the time (in milliseconds) that the service control manager should wait before performing the action that is specified in the Second Error setting. As an alternative, you can select one of the values from the list in this setting.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Action3">
<p>Select the action that you want the service control manager to perform the third and subsequent times that the service fails.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeService:Action3Delay">
<p>Specify the time (in milliseconds) that the service control manager should wait before performing the action that is specified in the Additional Errors setting. As an alternative, you can select one of the values from the list in this setting.</p>
</Topic>


<!-- Application Paths -->

<Topic id="VpeAppPath:Cat:General">
<p>Use the settings in the General area to configure an application path in your App-V package.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAppPath:Name">
<p>Enter the name of the executable file for which you want to create an application path.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAppPath:ExePath">
<p>Enter the path and file name of the executable file for which you want to create an application path.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic id="VpeAppPath:PathPrefix">
<p>Enter a semicolon-delimited list of fully qualified directories for the search path that the system should use to load DLLs and other files for the application. These directories are added to the beginning of the system PATH environment variable.</p>
</Topic>

</InlineHelp>